Register of the Martha Job papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Martha Job papers
1887-1962
1919-1941
74056
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 3 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder (3.7 linear feet)
Diary, maps, posters, photographs, clippings, and booklets relating to the Young Women's Christian Association in China, flood relief, the University of Peking, and internal problems in China from 1920 to 1928.
Job, Martha.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Martha Job was a Young Women's Christian Association (Y.W.C.A.) American Secretary in the Foreign Field worker, stationed in China from 1919 to 1929.
Scope and Content of Collection
Diary, maps, posters, pamphlets, photographic albums, newspaper clippings, and booklets relating to the Young Women's Christian Association (Y.W.C.A.) in China. The collection includes letters from Chinese students regarding the May 30, 1925 Shanghai student police riot, as well as posters and photographs from the "Better Babies" campaign.
Beijing da xue.; Young Women's Christian associations.; Education--China.; International relief.; Universities and colleges--China.; Women--China.
- Subject File, 1887-1962
  - Diary, 1923-1927 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Notes of Martha Job while working in China as a Y.W.C.A. American Secretary.
  - Printed matter relating to the University of Peking and internal problems in China, 1920-1945 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Contains letters and printed matter pertaining to the Shanghai student-police riot on May 20, 1925, and following protests. Also includes a circular from the Shanghai Laundry-men’s Guild discussing increases in fees for service and reduction in working hours, including price list (1927), as well as a variety of newspaper clippings and scrapbook pages pertaining to China, most notably from the San Francisco Chronicle and the North China Daily News.
  - Printed matter relating to the Y.W.C.A and women in China, 1921-1941 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Contains pamphlets and loose book pages regarding the Y.W.C.A and women in China, including Supplement to "The Green Year" Concerning the Events On and Since May 30 in Shanghai (July 1, 1925), and New Women in a New China, A Directory of the Young Women’s Christian Association in China (1923).
  - Miscellaneous, 1887-1962 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Includes letters, magazine clippings, and "Catalogue of Kodachrome Slides of Chinese Life and Culture" (March, 1962).
    Letter 1: Letter to Emperor Guang Xu and Empress Ci Xi (Empress Dowager) from Guang Yin of Jiang Nan Zhi Zao (Bureau of Weaving in regions south to the Yangtze River) 名称：江南织造广英奏光绪皇帝和慈禧皇太后 Date: September 6, 1887 日期：1886年9月6日（农历） Content: Report to the Emperor regarding the types, quantities, colors, expenses of supplies, fabric, papers, ink, etc. Mentioned General Zeng Guoquan participated in budget-related issues. 内容：上奏内容包括绢，纸，墨，等以及其款式，数量，颜色，材质，花销。内含曾国荃将军参办花费相关事宜。 The 5 red characters may be written by Emperor Huang Xu 亮点：“该衙门知道”5字具有光绪皇帝亲笔的可能性。
    Letter 2: Correspondence between Zeng Chong of Bureau of Weaving and Guang Xu Emperor 名称：江南织造增崇向光绪皇帝请安 Date: undated 日期：不详 Content: Sending a courtesy to the Emperor (contains Emperor Guang Xu’s response in red) 内容：江南织造增崇向光绪皇帝请安，内含光绪皇帝亲笔回复。
    Letter 3: Thank you letter to Emperor Guang Xu and Empress Ci Xi (Dowager) regarding Shi Gang’s appointment as the regional minister of custom at Huai An Gate (contains Emperor’s response) 名称：来自三院卿卫淮安关监督世纲的感谢信 （内含光绪皇帝答复） Date: November 28, 1902 日期：1902年11月28日（农历） Content: Shi Gang sends his appreciation and determination after his appointment as the regional minister of custom at Huai An Gate 内容：世纲向光绪皇帝表感谢和决心。
    Letter 4: Empty envelope and empty letter to Qing Emperor from Ming Zhi/Zheng of Jiang Xi Province 名称：二品顶戴江西广饶九南道兼管九江关税务明徵奏清皇帝（空白信纸和信封） Date and Content: N/A 日期：不详
    Magazine clippings contain images of Chinese architecture, including the Summer Palace and pagoda, and workers.
  - Maps and posters, 1920s
    - Travel map of Shanghai (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Flood map of Shanghai (Map case)
    - Five posters used in the "Better Babies" campaign, Hangchow, China, circa 1928 (Map case)
      See also: Photographs / Album 2, pp. 71-72
- Photographs, 1919-1929
  - Album 1, 1919-1923
    The album is a combination of travel photos and Y.W.C.A. photos. Most pages contain handwritten names, dates, and accounts by Job.
    Album starts in 1919 with Job's journey to China with other Y.W.C.A. foreign field secretaries (Georgia Hill, Elizabeth Wetherell, C. Huie, William Lockwood). The album contains photographs of the board and staff of Tientsin Y.W.C.A., Peking Y.W.C.A., Soochow University (1921), a baby welfare exhibit at Better Homes Institute Mokanshan (1920), and the Hangchow winter conference for non-mission schools (1921 to 1923).
    - Pages 1-84 (Box 2)
    - Pages 85-128 and covers with binding (Box 3)
  - Album 2, 1925-1929
    The album is a combination of travel photos and Y.W.C.A. photos. Most pages contain handwritten detail of names, dates, and accounts by Jobs.
    Album starts in 1925 with Job's return journey to China. The album contains photographs of Peking Y.W.C.A., Hangchow Y.W.C.A., and photos of Pootoo, sacred island of Buddhists. Images feature: Y.M.-Y.W.C.A. conference, Y.W.C.A. girls club activities, and "Better Babies" campaign from 1928 or 1929 (original posters as seen in photographs on pages 71-72 can be found in oversize folder in map case).
    - Pages 1-36 (Box 3)
    - Pages 37-74 and covers (Box 4)
  - Loose photographs, 1920s (Box 4)
    11 loose photographs depicting Peking, the Summer Palace, Hangchow, and Shanghai.